美国众神
前情提要
战争就要爆发了  影子
War is coming, Shadow.
如果我自己的儿子都不忠于我
And if I don't have the loyalty of my own son,
我又怎么能寄希望于别人的帮助呢
how can I expect support from anyone else?
你本来应该去湖畔镇的
You were supposed to go to Lakeside.
我已经不用听你的吩咐了
I don't do your bidding anymore.
我没什么可说的了
We're done.
你正走在从一无所有到无所不有的路上
You are on a path from nothing to everything.
我可以帮你  别搞丢了
I can help you. Don't lose this.
湖畔镇怎么样
What about Lakeside?
那里有一间公寓在等着你
You got an apartment waiting for you there.
我不需要
I'm good.
芝加哥  单程
Chicago, please. One way.
有一趟车可以
I do have one.
取消
准点到达
去往威斯康星的湖畔镇
Leaving for Lakeside, Wisconsin.
湖畔镇
先生  我的朋友艾莉森
Hey, mister! My friend, here, Alison...
祝您度过一个愉快的夜晚
Have a great night.
我叫安玛莉·辛泽曼
Ann-Marie Hinzelmann.
就是你需要搭车吧
You the fellow that needs a ride?
当大河孕育了初生子后
When the Great River gave birth to the First Ones,
它请求伊纳梅奇沃克  也就是雷鸟
they asked Inaemehkiwok, the Thunderbird,
守护我们
to watch over our people.
伊纳梅奇沃克让伟大的太阳温暖我们
Inaemehkiwok welcomed the Great Sun to warm us.
召唤来雨水滋润庄稼
Summoned the rain to make the crops grow,
并与米西基努比克  也就是长角巨蛇作战
and battled Misikinubik, the Great Horned Snake.
威斯康星印第安领地  1690年
伊纳梅奇沃克  请保护我们
伊纳梅奇沃克
Inaemehkiwok.
我们的好运用光了
暴风雪就要来了
很猛烈
气候之神
我将这个祭品献祭给霍德金  黑暗之神
请庇护我们免遭暴风雪的侵袭
天雷滚滚
闪电频现  神锤飞过天空
美国众神
第三季第二集
那个警察  柴德...什么的
The cop,Chad... something,
他把我放下就走了
he just dropped me off.
钥匙断在锁里了
The key broke off in the lock.
另一半钥匙  在我卫衣的左口袋里
Other half, it's in my left hoodie pocket.
左边
Left side.
转过来
Turn around.
我正想着你什么时候会出现呢
I was wondering when you'd show up.
我叫迈克  顺便一说
My name's Mike, by the way.
迈克·安塞尔
Mike Ainsel.
在这等着
Wait here.
下次再被锁门外了
Next time you get locked out,
记得先敲门  别瞎闯进来
knock on the door before you go breaking and entering.
我还不知道你的名字呢
I didn't catch your name, by the way.
喊我「物业经理」就行了
"Property Manager" works.
别动
影·穆恩
Shadow Moon.
我们一直在等你来
有很多事情需要你去做
似乎根本没办法保存
I can't seem to save anything.
老是崩溃
It just keeps crashing.
真有意思  美女
Interesting, ma'am.
你上一次升级系统是什么时候
When was the last time you did a system upgrade?
你以为自己这是在干什么
What do you think you're doing?
你知道规矩的
You know the rules.
好了  住手
Okay. Stop.
不许...碰我
No... touching.
我们玩得这些游戏...没一个起作用的
All these games we play... none of them work.
不  许  碰  我
You do not lay hands on me.
你之前从没这么做过
You've never done this before.
我不能碰你吗
I can't touch you?
我拥有世界上最大的IT公司
I own the biggest IT company in the world.
人人都对我有所求
Everyone wants something from me.
人人都想要我给予的东西
Everyone wants what I have to give.
我简直如同上帝
It's like I'm a fucking god.
所以我来这里  以求恢复一些平衡
So I come here to restore some balance.
因为我还以为你会和其他人不一样
Because I thought that you were different than the others.
没有人和我一样
There are no others like me.
我明白了
Oh, I see.
你很特别
You're special.
事实上  我  确实很特别
As a matter of fact, I am special.
那是因为我选择了和你共度良宵
Because I choose to spend my time with you.
不
No!
是因为我是个女神
Because I am a goddess.
你不过是在做戏
You're smoke and mirrors.
你就是个演员
And you're a showgirl.
而这是你的舞台
And this is your stage,
由威廉·亨廷顿·桑德斯支付购买
bought and paid for by William Huntington Sanders.
但你可以喊我比尔
But you can call me Bill.
你完全不知道我到底是谁
You have no idea who I am.
我当然知道你是谁
I know exactly who you are.
但我会展示给你看的
But I will show you.
这就是你想要的吗
Is this what you wanted?
我是比奇丝
I am Bilquis.
所有美丽的源泉
Mother of all beauty.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
天空因我而有色
I am the color of the sky!
太阳因我而生光
I give light to the sun!
而你
You...
什么都不是
...are nothing.
机密  本人亲启
科里亚达节
卓娅·维切恩亚亚家人邀请您一起追思
我们的晚间之星
我最亲爱的影子
My dearest Shadow.
我们必须谈谈你的头脑和内心
We must speak of your head and your heart.
邀请您来悼念我们的晚间之星
请尽快前来  卓娅·维切恩亚亚
Please attend. Urgently, Zorya Polunochnaya.
还有  别忘了带上硬币
Also, don't forget to bring the coin.
看在上帝的份上  迈克
For heaven's sake, Mike,
在你体温过低前快上车
get in the car before you get hypothermia!
在这样的天气下
In weather like this,
你穿着不合适的衣服在外面待了五分钟
you're out there for five minutes with improper attire,
一会儿你唯一能搭的车
and well, the only ride you're gonna need
就是去欧克莱尔验尸官那里的车
is to the coroner's in Eau Claire.
我正要进城买件外套
I was walking into town to buy a jacket.
幸好你长得帅
It's a good thing you're pretty.
看看这辆漂亮的老古董
Ah! Look at the beautiful clunker.
老古董
Clunker?
每年  我们找一辆报废的车
Every year, we take a wreck,
把它放在湖面上
we put it out on the lake,
然后  大家会猜测春天将至时
and then, folks guess the date and the time
废车压破冰面的日期和时间
when it'll break through the ice come spring.
然后  获胜者和高中平分奖金
And then, the winner splits the pot with the high school.
真的很有趣
It's really fun.
你会喜欢的
You're gonna love it.
湖畔镇
虽然湖畔镇以渔业闻名
Now, while Lakeside is known for its fishing,
全美最棒的馅饼之乡
但真正让我们出名的是好吃到死的馅饼
it's the to-die-for pasties that put us on the map.
圣诞馅饼
每一口都像温暖的拥抱
Every delicious bite is like a warm hug.
但你知道这地方最特别的是什么吗
But you know what really makes this place special?
是人
The people.
这里的每个人都真心关心他们的邻居
Everyone here genuinely cares for their neighbor.
这是我们一切行为的出发点
It's in everything we do.
这种精神是由本镇第一位
This spirit was passed down to us
居民及资助人莱斯特·汉密尔顿传给我们的
by the town's first citizen and benefactor, Lester Hamilton.
他死后  将财产留给了湖畔镇
And when he died, he left Lakeside his fortune
于是镇民才能继续繁荣昌盛
so that its citizens would continue to prosper.
他只要求我们尊重
All he asked in return was that we honor
一些他最喜欢的旧世界传统
some of his favorite Old World traditions.
所以每年我们都会举办一个冰雪节
So every year, we hold an ice festival
来庆祝他的慷慨
to celebrate his generosity
感谢我们神奇的小镇
and give thanks for our magical little town
以及此处的北欧传统
and its Nordic heritage.
我觉得你会喜欢这里的
I think you're gonna like it here.
不可抗力鼠脸假蝇鱼钩
Rat-Faced Irresistible.
一旦你有这些宝贝的消息传出去
The trout'll jump into your frying pan
鳟鱼都会自己跳进你的煎锅
once word gets out you got one of these babies.
安玛莉  你要把这可怜人的耳朵都唠叨掉了吗
You talking this poor man's ear off, Ann-Marie?
李·亨宁斯  店主
Lee Hennings, proprietor.
迈克·安塞尔
Mike Ainsel.
有什么事吗  安塞尔先生
What can we do for you, Mr. Ainsel?
你得给这家伙找件比运动衫
You need to get this fella into something warmer
更暖和的衣服
than a sweatshirt.
不用特别硬核的
Nothing too hardcore.
不知道我会在这个地方待多久
Not sure how long I'll be in this part of the country for.
他是戈尔曼街的新租客
He's the new tenant on Gorman Street.
戈尔曼
Gorman? Heh.
我们还在想什么时候会有人搬进去
We were wondering when somebody was gonna move in there.
欢迎
Welcome.
艾莉森  你能带安塞尔先生去看看大衣吗
Alison, can you show Mr. Ainsel the parkas, please?
圣诞节后  我们的毛衣也有大减价的活动
And we've got some great after-Christmas sales on sweaters, too.
谢谢
Thanks.
我记得你
Hey. I remember you.
昨晚  在巴士外面
Last night, outside of the bus,
我和我朋友太胡闹了  我很抱歉
um, my friend and I were being jerks. I'm sorry.
没关系的
Don't worry about it.
我今天过得很糟糕  让我开心一下吧
I was having a bad day. Made me smile.
好吧
Um, okay.
这是大衣
Uh, well, here are the parkas.
这是打折的毛衣
And, um, here are the on-sale sweaters,
不过就我来说  我会避开圣诞节款式的
although, personally, I'd avoid the Christmas ones.
它们超级土的
They're super lame.
好吧
Right. Okay.
看看这件怎么样
Let's see what this one looks like.
好了
Okay.
你觉得怎么样
What do you think?
不错
Amazing.
我是说  看起来很适合你
I mean... I mean it seems to fit you really well.
这对我来说就够了
Well, that is good enough for me.
我买了
I will take it.
那么  来看毛衣  有驯鹿的吗
Right, these sweaters. Anything in reindeer?
是的  有的
Uh, yeah, yes, I do.
艾莉森  我们卖安塞尔先生一张破车票怎样
What say we sell Mr. Ainsel a clunker ticket, Alison?
我正想问呢
I was just about to ask.
好了
Okay.
只需要选个日期和时间
Just need to, uh, pick a date and a time.
你觉得它什么时候会压穿冰层
When do you think it will go through the ice?
三月  破车
3月23日
March 23rd.
晚上七点到八点
7 p.m. till 8 p.m.
好吧  大多数人都会多选几天
Okay. Uh, most people pick more than one day.
但是  我猜这就是你的策略吧
But, uh, I guess this is your strategy.
就是这样
That's it.
好吧  我想我必须欣赏
Okay. Well, I guess I gotta admire
一个相信自己直觉的人
a man who goes with his instincts.
祝你好运  一共五美元
Good luck. Five dollars.
现在
Now...
哪颗牙
which one of your teeth...
松了呢
are loose, huh?
是这颗吗
Is it this one here? Ho!
没那么糟糕  不是吗
Now that wasn't so bad, was it?
没那么糟  你猜怎么着
No. Hey, I'll tell you what,
如果你能让我留下这颗臼齿做研究
I'll pay you twice the Tooth Fairy's going rate
我给你牙仙两倍的价钱
if I may keep this molar for my research.
好啊
Yeah!
泰瑞尔合作公司
我们的士兵最早是什么时候带着图腾去战斗的
When did our soldiers first carry our totems into battle?
古德弗雷德进攻法兰克但是搞砸了那时候
When Gudfred fucked up that Frankish business.
上一次是约克镇战役
The last time was Yorktown.
我们不再做黑森佣兵
We abandoned our post as Hessian Jaegers
然后加入了华盛顿的军队
and joined Washington's ranks.
战争的艺术有一半是知道何时转移阵营
Half the art of war is knowing when to switch sides.
你混得挺好
You have done well for yourself.
我还挺舒适的
Oh, I'm comfortable.
提尔  北欧战神  舒适
Tyr, the warlord, comfortable?
角斗士的杀戮欲
Well, the gladiator's bloodlust
卖相不太好
doesn't make for a very lucrative business.
但是如果你需要战神出场
Ha! But if it's a war god you want...
我只需要你捐个款就行
All I want from you is a donation.
我受宠若惊
Oh, I'm flattered.
冬至暖愉
爱你
德墨忒尔
你大老远过来
You came all this way
你本来可以在芝加哥见我
when you could have put the touch on me in Chicago.
科里亚达节
At the Koliada?
是的  没错
Oh, yeah.
科里亚达节
卓娅·维切恩亚亚家人邀请您一起追思
我们的晚间之星
芝加哥
Chicago.
为了卓娅·维切恩亚亚
For Zorya Vechernyaya.
不能等到那个时候吗
Couldn't wait 'til then?
起诉战争是一个费时费力的差事
Prosecuting the war is an all-consuming endeavor.
总有事情在最后一刻出现
Things come up all the time, last minute.
虽然追悼会是好的
Memorials are all well and good,
但是我们都知道以牙还牙
but we both know that an eye for an eye
并不便宜
don't come cheap.
一切为了事业
Well, anything for the cause.
我该署名
Should I make it out to...?
卡什[现金]就好了
"Cash" Will be just fine.
真大方
Very generous.
我在你身边战斗  奥丁
战斗至死  或者杀死我们的敌人
你的牙怎么样
How are your teeth?
想得美
Nice try.
早上好啊  萨尔
Oh, top of the morning to you, Sal!
好了  我说到哪了  对
All right, where was I? Oh, right!
湖畔新闻社就在那边
Okay, Lakeside News is just down that-a-way.
是扎克里·摩根在1902年创建的
It was started by Zachary Morgan in 1902.
他得了梅毒  穿着尿不湿死的  可怜的家伙
He died of syphilis wearing a diaper, poor fella.
真不错  其实
Nice. Um, so actually...
安迪  但愿你是在给你老婆买礼物
Andy! I hope you're looking for a present for your wife!
你们两个的结婚纪念日马上到了
Your anniversary is coming up.
他经常忘记一些事情
He happens to forget things
像结婚纪念日这种  一年一次的婚姻事件
like annual marital events, like anniversaries.
梅宝家餐馆就在这边
Mabel's Restaurant is right over here,
那里的馅饼  就像我之前说的
and the pasties, as I mentioned earlier,
简直棒极了
are the best things ever.
你知道吗  她传承了她奶奶的配方
You know, she inherited the recipe from her grandmother,
而她奶奶是从康沃尔郡带来的
who brought it over here from Cornwall.
我能不能快速插一句
If I could just sneak in
问一下我在哪里能租一辆车
a quick question about where to rent a car.
那你应该找欧克莱尔  那
Oh, that's Eau Claire, that...
我从玛莎那里听说凯西的内衣被偷了
I heard from Martha that Kathy's unmentionables were stolen
而且是直接从洗衣篮里偷的
right from her laundry basket!
我知道  我知道
I know, I know, I know.
我们先不要因为一点点谣言
Let's not all get in a fuss
就大惊小怪的
over the Piggly Wiggly rumor mill.
-你好啊  安玛丽  -你好  柴德
- Oh, hey, Ann-Marie. - Hi, Chad.
迈克  看起来李·亨宁斯把你照顾得挺好啊
Oh, Mike. I see Lee Henning's taken good care of you.
现在你看起来更像本地人了
Now you're lookin' more local.
至少暖和了不少
Lot warmer at least.
梅格·冈瑟在激动什么呢
What's Meg Gunther in a lather about?
内衣
Lingerie.
显然  她的一周一轮的内衣丢了三套
Apparently, three pairs of her days-of-the-week underwear:
星期三的  星期四的和星期六的
Wednesday, Thursday, and Saturday,
全从烘干机里消失了
all went missing from the dryer.
所以她就认为  我们有一个  在逃内衣贼
So, in her mind, we have a, uh, panty thief on the loose.
你看  迈克  这就算得上
See, Mike, this is what qualifies
湖畔镇的重罪了
as major crime here in Lakeside.
俗话说得好  如果你有钱  你在蒙特卡洛生活
You know, if you're rich, you live in Monte Carlo.
如果你出名  就住在加州
And if you're famous, you live in California.
但是如果你很幸运  那你就住在这  湖畔镇
But if you're lucky, you live here in... in Lakeside.
该死  我要去水湾那里找巴特了
Oh, shoot. I'm supposed to meet Bart up at the inlet.
太抱歉了  柴德
I am so sorry. Um, hey, Chad,
你能不能带我们的新人去尝尝馅饼
could you get our newest resident situated with a pasty?
你根本不用再问我第二遍
Oh, you don't have to ask me twice.
-我要饿死了  -太好了
- I'm starving. - Okay.
-来吧  -好了
- Come on. - All right.
-谢谢你  -你肯定会喜欢的
- Thank you. - You're gonna love it.
你知道吗  有趣的是
You know, interestingly, uh,
梅宝的美味馅饼配方
Mabel's amazing pasty recipe,
其实她是传承她奶奶的
she actually inherited from her grandmother.
大老远从康沃尔郡来的
Came all the way from Cornwall.
坐吧
Grab a seat.
早上好啊  亲爱的
How you doing this morning, sweetie?
梅宝  这是迈克
Hey, Mabel, this is Mike.
他住在戈尔曼街
He's staying up at the spot on Gorman.
很高兴认识你  迈克
It's nice to meet you, Mike.
要看看菜单吗  亲爱的
Can I show you a menu, hon?
大家都在说馅饼
Well, everyone's been talking about these pasties.
一份馅饼  店里赠送
One pasty on the house it is.
免费赠送给第一次光顾的顾客
It's complimentary to first-time customers.
谢谢  能不能再来杯咖啡
Thank you. Can I get a coffee too?
我已经知道这牛仔要吃什么了
I already know what this cowboy's having.
穆里根局长
Chief Mulligan.
你好
Hey, there.
你好啊
What's good?
别让我干等着  小子
Don't leave me hanging, dawg.
你认识德瑞克吗
You know Derek?
不认识
No.
我觉得他只是想让我知道有他这么个人
I think he just wants me to know he's down.
你是做什么工作的  迈克
So, what do you do for a living, Mike?
现在就替我叔叔干活
Just working for my uncle right now.
他是做什么的
What's he do?
他做进出口贸易
He runs an import-export business.
是吗  哪一种
Yeah? What kind?
大部分都是古董
Antiques, mostly.
我语气像警察问话  对吧
I sound like a cop, don't I?
有一点
Little bit.
习惯成自然
Yeah, that's a force of habit.
天啊  迈克  对不起
Jeez, Mike, I'm sorry.
-我不是故意要打听  -没事
- I don't mean to pry. - It's all good.
吃的来了  先生们
Here you go, gents.
谢谢
Thank you.
小心点
Now, careful.
如果你饿着肚子离开这里
If you leave here hungry,
那就是你自己的错
it's your own dang fault.
真好吃
So good.
小心  这些会上瘾的
Careful. They're addictive.
你也许知道
You might know.
有比欧克莱尔更近的租车地方吗
Is there anywhere closer than Eau Claire to rent a car?
「湖畔镇日报」
新酒店开张
暴风雨后码头需要修葺
你好
Hey, there.
看看谁和我一起来了
Look who I got with me.
柴德
Hi, Chad.
安塞尔先生
Mr. Ainsel.
房管小姐
Ms. Property Manager.
这么说你们俩见过了
So, you two have met.
在枪口下认识的
At gun point.
安塞尔先生昨晚想闯进他的公寓
Mr. Ainsel tried to break into his apartment last night.
因为钥匙不好使
Due to a key malfunction.
幸好没人受伤
Fortunately, no one was hurt.
更明智的做法
Well, the wiser course of action
应该是打电话给当地的执法部门
would have been to call your local law enforcement.
「湖畔镇日报」
迈克想找交通工具
Mike here is looking for some transportation,
我想到了桑迪的旧车
and, Sandy's old beater came to mind.
那辆车不卖
The car is not for sale.
车子已经停在后面差不多两年了
It's... been parked out back better part of two years now.
潜在紧急情况
Possible 10-99.
从马里埃尔·拉森的福特福莱克斯车
Bag of laundry taken out
发现了的洗衣店袋子
of Mariel Larson's Ford Flex.
强盗又来了
Bandit strikes again.
立刻赶过去
10-76.
「湖畔镇日报」
事先声明
For the record,
我只是想租车
I was only lookin' to rent the car.
只是想去芝加哥
Just trying to get to Chicago.
为什么要去芝加哥
What's in Chicago?
参加朋友的追悼会
Memorial service for a friend.
今天下午就走
I leave this afternoon.
也许你要等个一两天
You may want to wait a day or two.
暴风雨过后州际公路总是一片混乱
The interstate's always a mess after a storm.
今晚我得去那里
I need to be there tonight.
但明天我就回来了
But I'll be back tomorrow.
两天一百美元
A hundred dollars for the two days.
把车完好无损地开回来
Bring it back like you found it.
如果我把车洗了呢
If I get it cleaned up?
一百五十美元
A hundred and fifty.
这是唯一一把钥匙  别弄断了
That's the only key. Try not to break it.
谢谢
Thank you.
真主至上
Allahu akbar.
你怎么会来开罗
What brings you back to Cairo?
"我的新任务对星期三先生来说至关重要
"My new mission is of vital importance to Mr. Wednesday.
我不知道需要多长时间
I don't know how long it will take
或是我会离开多久
or how long I will be gone.
就当这是我们旅程的终点吧
Consider this the end of our journey.
别找我"
Don't look for me."
所以你对这个"任务"一无所知吗
So you know nothing of this "Mission"?
我已经好几月没见到星期三先生
I haven't seen or heard anything
也没有他的消息
from Mr. Wednesday in months.
我只知道
All I know is whatever task
星期三给精灵指派的任务
Wednesday has demanded of the Jinn,
让我们从此分离
it has driven us apart.
但也许是精灵自己决定的呢
But perhaps the Jinn made up his own mind?
感觉会变
Feelings can change.
如果他真的不爱我了
If he truly does not love me,
我要听他当面告诉我
I need to hear him say it to my face.
我要去芝加哥参加科里亚达节
Well, I'm due in Chicago for the festival of Koliada.
旧神们聚集在一起悼念
The Old Gods are assembling to honor the ascendance
卓娅·维切恩亚亚灵魂的归升
of Zorya Vechernyaya's soul.
精灵也会参加吗
And the Jinn will be there?
有这个可能
Uh, it's... possible.
我甘愿下七层地狱
I would endure the seven gates of hell
去了解他内心的想法
to know the truth in his heart.
临时混带  S·奥尔森
♪我知道  你不会回来♪
♪ I... know you won't come back ♪
♪我也知道可能是我的错♪
♪ And I... know that it might be my fault ♪
♪我有很多事想...♪
♪ And I've... got a lot to... ♪
我去趟超市  桑迪
I'm off to the store, Sandy.
妈  我录音呢
Mom. I'm recording.
抱歉  别忘了
Oh, sorry. Listen, don't forget,
你答应过练习之后去接里昂
you promised to pick up Leon after practice. Okay?
我爱和你在一起的每一个时刻  卓娅
I loved every moment together with you, Zorya.
但是我讨厌你做的饭
But I hated the food you cooked...
打心底讨厌
...with my entire soul.
对不起
I'm sorry.
每一顿都在不断变差
Every meal worse than the last.
祝你回家一路顺风
I wish you a safe journey home.
我的朋友们
My friends.
敬我们最爱的卓娅·维切恩亚亚
To our beloved Zorya Vechernyaya.
干杯
Skol!
你怎么来了
What the hell are you doing here?
我说  你怎么来了
I said, what the hell are you doing here?
出去  没邀请你来
Out. You were not invited.
也没邀请我  可我还是来了
Neither was I! But here I am.
该死
Oh, shit.
没有晚间之星的引导
Without our evening star to guide us,
我们的天空将永远阴暗
the firmament is forever dimmed!
他们两个
Oh, the two of them!
你不是应该在湖畔镇吗
Shouldn't you be in Lakeside?
她是位非常特别的女士
Look, she was a special lady.
我不是来找麻烦的
I didn't come for any trouble.
礼物放在那边的桌子上
Gifts go over there to table.
是  我带来了...
Yeah, I brought, I brought...
就放那一堆上  礼物
Yeah. The same pile. Gift.
烟给我  我想要
The cigarette, I want.
节哀顺变
I'm sorry for your loss.
非常好
Very well done.
米歇尔·斯马特  「旧情重燃在斐济」
这孩子进步了
The kid's learning.
但是你遗忘了最重要的部分
But, you missed the most important bit of all.
出自丹麦首都大区最棒的芝士工厂
From the finest cheese laboratory in Hovedstaden,
三倍熏培哈瓦蒂干酪来抚恤失去的伤痛  同志
thrice-fumed Havarti to ease the pain of loss, comrade.
对于卓娅·乌特恩亚亚
And for Zorya Utrennyaya,
一份心意帮你暂时逃离
a token that you may temporarily escape
失去姐妹的痛苦
the agony of losing a sister.
她是个冷血性感的贱人
She was a cold-hearted, sexy bitch.
她为什么喜欢你  我一点也不明白
And why she liked you, I don't understand.
我理解不了
It's beyond me.
而你  我想我们还有事没完
And you, I think we have some unfinished business.
我不在乎
I don't care
你会不会护住你那漂亮的头骨
if you try to cover that nice skull.
我的锤子与它的约定尚在
My hammer still has an appointment with it.
我可以肯定这不是邀请我来的原因
Pretty sure that's not why I was invited.
没邀请你来
You were not invited.
客人名单上绝对有我
Well, definitely on the guest list.
这字真漂亮  失传的艺术
Outstanding calligraphy. It's a lost art.
你妹妹邀请了他
Your sister invited him.
我现在能致礼了吗
Can I pay my respects now?
好  你可以去楼顶
Yes, you can pay your respect
进行致礼了  现在
by going up to the roof. Now.
今晚  你和我
Tonight, you and I
喝到大脑麻木
will drink ourselves stupid,
屎尿横流
piss ourselves,
一同回忆卓娅·维切恩亚亚的
and remember the wisdom and beauty
智慧与美丽
of Zorya Vechernyaya.
不许你提她的名字
Hey, you take that name out of your mouth.
现在不是说这些的时候
Oh, this is not the place or the time...
沃坦  听好了  这是你的错
Votan! Listen, you did this.
你基本上等同于扣下了扳机
You as good as pulled the trigger of the gun
结束了她的生命
that ended her life.
她是被共同的敌人谋杀的
She was murdered by shared enemies.
你好大的胆子  沃坦
The balls on you, Votan.
你是来向卓娅致敬的吗
Are you here to pay your respect to Zorya?
我觉得不是  你来是为了你那愚蠢的战争
I don't think so. You're here because of your stupid war.
这是罪过吗
Is that a sin?
我来这里是为了悼念
I came here to mourn the death
我曾心爱之人
of someone who once owned my heart,
同时发现自己周围站满了
and at the same time find myself surrounded
斯拉夫不同种族的神明
by Slavic deities of every stripe.
能被召集于我们旗下的盟友
A cotillion of allies to be recruited to our cause.
还是说  你忘了我们的事业
Or... have you forgotten our cause?
你是不是忘记了
Has it slipped your mind
你  岑诺伯格  夜神
that you, Czernobog, the Dark One,
曾发誓效忠于我
swore an oath to me?
敬晚间之星
To the evening star.
我喜欢你的发型
I like the hair.
看起来很有型
Much better look.
改头换面的时候到了
It was time for a change.
你把硬币带来了吗
Did you bring the coin?
是的
Yeah.
我走到哪里都带着
I carry it everywhere.
因为你和它一样
Because you are just like it.
总是一半在光明  一半在黑暗之中
Always half in light, half in shadow.
你有一部分总是不肯示人
Part of you always hidden from sight.
星象告诉我们
The stars tell that a day
总有一天你会面对两个选择
is coming when you will face two paths.
你必须选择自己的命运
You must choose which way your destiny unfolds.
我唯一想要的命运就是正常的生活
The only destiny I want is a normal life.
你这么说  但是
You say that, but...
你的思维和心灵并不统一
...your head and your heart are not in agreement.
你的一半来自于全能的父
Half of you comes from the All-Father.
它诱惑你  他的权力
It tempts you. His power,
他的过去
his... history.
好吧  告诉你我想要什么
Okay, this is what I want.
我不想再猜谜了
I want no more riddles.
你懂吗  不再有含义模糊的答案
You know? No... no more cryptic answers.
星象只能揭示这么多
The stars can only reveal so much.
但是  当你迷茫的时候
But, when you cannot see your way,
夜空会指引你
the night sky will guide you.
这才值得我跑一趟
That was worth the drive.
那些新众神
Ah, these New Gods,
杀了我们挚爱的卓娅
that killed our beloved Zorya,
如果他们想要战争  那就开战
if they want a war, bring me war, huh?
现在听我说  岑诺伯格
Now, hear me, Czernobog!
我  沃坦  全能的父
I, Votan, the All-Father,
发誓为卓娅的死报仇!
swear to avenge Zorya's death!
邀请所有人  还有所有热血沸腾的混蛋
And invite all, and any, hot-blooded bastards
帮助恢复真神的荣耀
to help restore honor to the true gods!
除了我  他真的邀请了所有人
He really did invite everyone but me.
偷得不错
Nice lift.
我不知道你在说什么
I don't know what you're talking about.
那个明信片  我不会注意到吗
The postcard. What, I wouldn't notice?
但在你去拜访她之前
But before you pay her a visit,
问问自己能给她带去什么
ask yourself if you have anything to offer her
除了心痛
except for heartache.
管好你自己
Stay in your fucking lane.
我的孩子
My boy.
你个混蛋  星期三
You asshole, Wednesday!
你骗了我
You lied to me!
也愿你平安  兄弟
Oh, well, now, "Salaam aleikum" To you too, brother.
见鬼去吧  你把他送走了
The hell with that! You sent him away!
我没有
I did not!
那个鸡奸者讨厌我
That sodomite hates me
对我恨之入骨
with every hair on his chinny-chin-chin.
求你了  我要找到他
Please. I need to find him.
在他甩了你之后吗
After the way he pumped and dumped you?
算了吧
Get over it.
你应该让妖精杀了他
You should have let the leprechaun kill him.
有一天你会感谢我的
One day you'll thank me.
我  我要走了
I'm, uh... I'm out.
回湖畔镇
Back to Lakeside?
那地方越来越吸引你了  不是吗
The place grows on you, doesn't it?
几乎被冻死两次
Nearly froze to death twice
又差点被爆头
and almost got my head blown off.
但没错  食物很好
But, yeah, food's good.
我会联系你的  米格尔
I'll be in touch, Miguel.
我觉得我的车很性感
I thought my ride was sexy.
你在做什么
What's your hustle?
你是被包养了吗
You a sugar baby?
你和金主有问题吗
You got daddy issues?
我只是在做我自己
I'm just doing me.
那是什么
Which means what?
扮演老男人的未婚妻
Playing the old man's fiancee?
那不是
That would be a no.
我是女队的一员
I'm on the all-girls squad.
那你是怎么跟他在一起的
So, how'd you end up with him?
他在克雷格列表网上发的贴子太棒了
Oh, his Craigslist post was dope,
所以我回复「有兴趣」
so I replied, "Interested".
接下来我只知道
Next thing I know,
我开着贝蒂  拿到现金报酬
I'm driving Betty and getting paid in cash.
好吧  你知道吗
All right. You know what?
我不在乎
I don't care.
我大三的时候
My junior year of Hunter,
被开除了  因为做黑客被捕了
I got kicked out, arrested for hacking.
我欠了一屁股债
Up to my ass in debt.
完美的工作
When along comes the perfect job,
在我最需要的时候来临了
right when I needed it.
克雷格列表
Craigslist.
他帮我付清了律师费和学费
He paid off my legal bills and tuition.
我帮他处理高科技的事
I help him with... um, tech stuff.
好消息是
Well, the good news is,
因为我  你现在可以联系到你老爸了
on account of me, you can now reach your old man,
无论何时
day or night.
电话亭是怎么回事
What happened to the phone booths?
是吧  海拉程序
Right? Hella progress.
听着  我和我老爸有很多麻烦事
Look, I got all sorts of shit with my old man,
但也许你可以考虑一下你爸爸
but maybe consider your Pops
不完全是个混蛋
isn't a complete fucking asshole.
这有点困难
Now, that is a stretch.
我懂
I hear you.
如果你需要一个朋友聊聊
But if you ever need a friendly voice,
我知道  不是他
I get it, not him,
打给那个号码吧
just call the number.
你起码会接通我
You'll get me, at least.
好吧  听着  当事情变得难以处理时
All right, listen. When it all gets too much to handle,
总会这样的
and it will.
一样的
Likewise.
那边发生什么了
What the hell is going on in there?
星期三
Wednesday.
湖畔镇
你好  梅宝
Hey, Mabel.
怎么了
Yes?
如果我再点馅饼的话
If I have another one of those pasties,
恐怕吃四个都不够
I'm gonna want four more.
所以我还是悠着点
So I am gonna take it easy
这次我就点
and I will have, uh,
培根配小麦土司吧
bacon and wheat toast, please.
有什么问题吗
Everything all right?
柴德
Hey, Chad!
湖畔镇警局
迈克
Hey, Mike.
我得问你几个问题
I'm gonna have to ask you some questions.
你下午四点出发去芝加哥
You left for Chicago about 4 p.m.
离开镇子之前停车加油了
You stop for gas before you left town?
谢谢
Thank you.
对
Yeah.
在小镇大街的西铁古加油站
The, uh, the CITGO at, uh, Main.
怎么了
What's up?
艾莉森·麦戈文昨天没去上学
Alison McGovern didn't show up to school
也没去上班
or work yesterday.
她前天在亨宁斯店里下班之后
No one's seen or heard from her
再就没人见过她  也没有过她的消息
since her shift ended at Hennings the previous day.
迈克  要知道  这不是针对你
Gotta understand, Mike, this is nothing personal.
我们要梳理一下你过去72小时的行踪
We're going to go over your whereabouts for the past 72.
而且迈克  我需要你说得越详细越好
And Mike, I need you be as specific as you can.
没问题  去芝加哥
Sure. It took about
用了差不多七个小时
seven hours to get to Chicago.
你是去参加追悼会的
You were there for a memorial service.
是家人吗
This a family member?
我叔叔的朋友
Friend of my uncle's.
我住在...
Yeah, I stayed at the, um,
东俄亥俄州的手绘酒店
Freehand Hotel, East Ohio.
然后今天早晨开回来的
And drove back this morning.
挡风玻璃怎么回事
The windshield?
我在36号公路撞了一只鹿
I hit a deer on Route 36.
在斯蒂文斯波恩特的一家维修厂修了玻璃
The mechanic shop in Stevens Point fixed it.
好了  迈克  我需要你
Okay, Mike. I am gonna need you
把你准确的行车路线写下来
to write down the exact route that you took
我们要核查高速监控录像
so we can confirm that with highway surveillance cameras.
还需要
Also gonna
扣留车辆做一下鲁米诺试验
need to hang on to the vehicle for a Luminol test.
好的
Sure.
不能用个鬼
Fuck it.
迈克  等等
Hey, Mike. Wait, is...
这是给不允许你用的壁炉烧的吗
Is that for the fireplace you're not allowed to use?
这样吧  干脆崩了我算了
You know what? Just shoot me.
行吗  这次来真的
Okay? For real this time.
因为这样比冻死
Because it's a lot quicker way to go
痛快得多
than just freezing to death.
也许我们两个一开始就有些误会
I think maybe you and I got off on the wrong foot.
我跟柴德聊过了
I spoke to Chad.
他说你的事都核实无误
He said your story checks out.
芝加哥  挡风玻璃
Chicago, the windshield.
对不起
I'm sorry.
有艾莉森的消息吗
Anything on Alison?
跟她的几个朋友谈了谈
Talked to some of her friends.
谁也不知道她有什么要离开镇子的缘由
No one knows any reason why she might have left town
也不知道她可能去哪里
or where she could've gone.
她家人正四处张贴传单
The family's putting up fliers
请求志愿者帮助搜寻
and asking for volunteers to help in a search.
需要帮忙就叫我
Let me know if I can help.
迈克
Look, Mike...
我用猎枪招呼你的事
The thing with the shotgun.
确实不太好
That wasn't cool.
对  是不好
No. It wasn't.
我之前把暖气的开关关上了
I had the breaker for the furnace turned off.
这没人住  干嘛给空房间供暖
No one was living here. Why heat an empty place?
差点忘了给你这个
Oh, uh, almost forgot to give you this.
我没让修车厂的人扔掉
I got the guys at the body shop to save it.
估计你儿子回来的时候可能想要
Figured your son might want it when he got back.
他在哪上学  你没说过
Where's he at school? You didn't say.
佛罗里达州
Florida.
不错  学什么专业的
Nice. What's he studying?
如果暖气不热了
Uh, if your heat goes out,
或者你想封窗户  需要帮忙的话
or you want some help insulating those windows,
直接叫我就行
you know where to find me.
BGM: Little Margaret  by
Rhiannon Giddens, Francesco Turrisi
♪ Little Margaret sitting in her high hall chair ♪
♪ Combing back her long, yellow hair ♪
♪ She saw sweet William and his new-made bride ♪
♪ Riding up the road so near ♪
♪ She threw down her ivory comb ♪
♪ Threw back her long yellow hair ♪
♪ Said, "I'll go down and I'll bid him farewell ♪
♪ And I'll nevermore go there" ♪
♪ It was late in the night They were fast asleep ♪
♪ Little Margaret appeared ♪
♪ all dressed in white ♪
♪ Standing at their bed-feet ♪
♪ For I want to kiss those cold, cold lips ♪
♪ For I know they'll never ♪
♪ Kiss mine ♪
♪ Three times he kissed her cold, cold hand ♪
♪ Twice he kissed her cheek ♪
♪ But once he kissed her cold cold lips ♪
♪ Then he fell in her arms asleep ♪